Finding Aid for the Knox Mellon Collection of Material About the John Birch Society and Other Radical Conservative Organizations and Causes LSC.1102
UCLA Library Special Collections
Knox Mellon collection of material about the John Birch Society and other radical conservative organizations and causes
1918-1968
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mellon, Knox
LSC.1102
17.5 Linear Feet (35 boxes and 1 oversize box)
William Knox Mellon, Jr. (b.1925) was a professor of history at Immaculate Heart College, the Democratic nominee for the California 24th District for Congress (1962), and the treasurer for the Oral History Association. The collection consists of periodicals and various publications of the John Birch Society, clippings and documents of the Pasadena-based Network of Patriotic Letter Writers, and papers and clippings of several political campaigns in Southern California.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942334053606533
Biography/History
William Knox Mellon, Jr. was born on October 20, 1925 in Houston, Texas; BA, Pomona College, 1950; MA, Claremont College, 1953; Ph.D, Claremont Graduate School, 1972; became a professor of history at Immaculate Heart College; Democratic nominee for the California 24th District for Congress, 1962; became treasurer, Oral History Association.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of periodicals and various publications of the John Birch Society, clippings and documents of the Pasadena-based Network of Patriotic Letter Writers, and papers and clippings of several political campaigns in Southern California.
History teachers -- California -- Los Angeles.; John Birch Society; Mellon, Knox -- Archives
- John Birch Society Materials
  - The Fascist Revival. The Inside Story of the John Birch Society. New York: New Century., 1961 (Box 3)
  - John Birch Society Appreciation and Encouragement., 1960 (Box 23)
  - John Birch Society national finance committee: A frank report., 1963 (Box 23)
  - American Opinion Dollar Reprint Series: "The California report on the John Birch Society.", 1963 (Box 10)
  - The life of John Birch. Boston/Los Angeles: Western Islands., 1954 (Box 12)
  - John Birch Society Bulletin., 1959-64 (Box 13)
    Scope and Contents note
    October-November 1959.
    February-March, May-July, September-December 1960.
    January-November 1961.
    January-October, December 1962.
    January-May, July-September, December 1963.
    January-May 1964.
  - John Birch Society Member's monthly message., March 1964 (Box 23)
  - The pink book of the John Birch Society for 1963. (Box 23)
  - The John Birch Society is a threat to whom?, n.d. (Box 24)
  - John Birch Society: letter to George Romney., September 1, 1962 (Box 24)
  - The Life of John Birch. In the story of one American boy, the ordeal of his age. Chicago: Henry Regenery Company., 1954 (Box 25)
  - Files - GOP and Birch smear., 1963 (Box 27)
  - Files - John Birch Society news clippings., 1963-64 (Box 33)
- Federal and National Government Materials
  - Committee on Un-American Activities, U.S. House of Representatives., 1956-63 (Box 14)
    Various publications.
  - Special committee to investigate tax-exempt foundations and comparable organizations., 1954 (Box 14)
    Report.
  - Subversive activities control board., June 30, 1956 (Box 14)
    Sixth annual report.
  - Senate fact-finding subcommittee on un-American activities. State of California., 1955, 1959-63 (Box 14)
    Annual reports.
  - State of Louisiana. Joint legislative committee on un-American activities., 1957, 1963-64 (Box 14)
    Reports.
  - Special preparedness subcommittee of the committee on armed services. United States Senate., 1962 (Box 15)
    Hearings and report.
  - Senate investigating committee on education., 1949-59 (Box 16)
    Various annual reports.
  - Joint interim committee on the public education system., 1961 (Box 16)
  - Hearings and reports from the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations., 1959-64 (Box 16)
  - Hearings and reports from the House and Senate Judiciary Committees., 1919, 1958-63 (Box 16)
  - "Special report of the county counsel on problem created by recent U.S. Supreme Court cases affecting the Communist Party and the twenty year fight of the county of Los Angeles against subversion and communism.", August 19, 1964 (Box 28)
- Miscellaneous Materials
  - Various pamphlets, speeches and brochures., 1955-64 (Box 15)
  - Governor's conference for department heads and deputies. [California]., September 10-11, 1959 (Box 23)
  - International stability and progress: United States interests and instruments. The American Assembly, Graduate School of Business, Columbia University., May 2-5, 1957 (Box 23)
- Goldwater Campaign
  - Goldwater campaign material., 1964 (Box 29)
  - Citizens for Goldwater-Miller victory manual., 1964 (Box 29)
- Organizations
  - The American Tariff League., 1958 (Box 17)
  - Church League of America., n.d. (Box 17)
  - Citizens Foreign Aid Committee., 1964 (Box 17)
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, Long Beach., 1966-68 (Box 17)
  - Fire and police research association of Los Angeles., 1963 (Box 18)
  - International documents service., 1959-60 (Box 18)
  - The Movement to Impeach Earl Warren., n.d. (Box 18)
  - National Defense Committee, National Society, Daughters of the American Revolution., n.d. (Box 18)
  - Network of Patriotic Letter Writers., 1959-62 (Box 18)
  - Network of Patriotic Letter Writers., 1962-64 (Box 20)
    Bulletins, reports, articles, "important letters to write."
  - Network of Patriotic Letter Writers - mailings., 1966-68 (Box 29)
  - Lincoln Club of Los Angeles., n.d. (Box 18)
  - Facts in Education Incorporated., 1956-63 (Box 18)
  - Documents of Freedom., n.d. (Box 21)
  - Council on Foreign Relations., 1949-61 (Box 28)
  - National Council of Churches, and communism documentation., 1955-60 (Box 28)
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade - mailings., 1966 (Box 29)
- Files, 1951-68
  - Cheddi Jagan of Guiana., 1961-63 (Box 26)
  - Jamaica., n.d. (Box 26)
  - Japan., 1962 (Box 26)
  - The Jenks case., 1959-61 (Box 26)
  - Jiminez[sic], Marcos Perez., 1963 (Box 26)
  - Katanga - The Congo - Tshombe., 1962-63 (Box 26)
  - Bobby Kennedy and communists., 1963-64 (Box 26)
  - Kennedy-Rusk policies., 1961-63 (Box 26)
  - Kennedy - Khrushchev., 1963 (Box 26)
  - Kennedy's cabinet and appointments., 1962-63 (Box 26)
  - Korea., 1959-63 (Box 26)
  - Kuchel, Thomas H. - smears., 1961-63 (Box 26)
  - Latin America - Caribbean., 1963 (Box 26)
  - Lattimore, Outer Mongolia and Oppenheimer., 1961-63 (Box 26)
  - Gen. Douglas McArthur., 1951, 1963 (Box 26)
  - Mexico - Baja California., 1961-63 (Box 26)
  - Middle East - Jordan, Egypt, Syria., 1962 (Box 26)
  - Middle East - Laos, Vietnam., 1963 (Box 26)
  - Mikoyan, Roslov., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Mongolia, Mauretania., 1961 (Box 26)
  - Moral Re-armament., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Attorney Stanley Mosk., 1962 (Box 26)
  - Mosk, Attorney Gen. Stanley., 1962 (Box 26)
  - Minute Man Network - Alerts., 1959-60 (Box 26)
  - Castro blackmail., 1959-63 (Box 27)
  - Central America - Honduras., 1963 (Box 27)
  - Congo., 1961-64 (Box 27)
  - Congress. Directory of the 89th., 1965 (Box 27)
  - Costa Rica., 1960-63 (Box 27)
  - Cuba as base for spreading communism., 1962-63 (Box 27)
  - Cuba - Castro., 1960-63 (Box 27)
  - Dominican Republic., 1963 (Box 27)
  - Egypt - Israel - Yemen - Near East., 1961-63 (Box 27)
  - Free China, Korea., 1959-63 (Box 27)
  - Facts in education., 1964-65 (Box 27)
  - Gold reserve, George R. Jordan., 1958-61 (Box 27)
  - Government secrecy., 1958 (Box 27)
  - Guatemala., 1963 (Box 27)
  - Haiti - Dominican Republic., 1963 (Box 27)
  - Alger Hiss., 1962-63 (Box 27)
  - J. Edgar Hoover's removal., 1960-61 (Box 27)
  - Human events., 1965 (Box 27)
  - Hungary., 1961-63 (Box 27)
  - International Court of Justice., 1959 (Box 27)
  - Italy - Pope., 1963 (Box 27)
  - Yorty, Mayor Sam., 1961-67 (Box 27)
  - Radio., 1958-59 (Box 30)
  - Reading Reform Foundation., 1963 (Box 30)
  - Red China., 1959-62 (Box 30)
  - Research Institute report., 1965 (Box 30)
  - Walter Reuther., 1965 (Box 30)
  - Rostow, Walt W. (Foreign Policy)., 1962 (Box 30)
  - Labor strikes - Hoffa-Reuther Bridges., 1959-63 (Box 30)
  - Major Arch E. Roberts, USAR., 1962-63 (Box 30)
  - Rousselot, John., 1961-62 (Box 30)
  - South America to the left., 1961-62 (Box 30)
  - State Department., 1961-64 (Box 30)
  - State Department, Bryton Barron., 1956-59 (Box 30)
  - State Dept. - mutual security reduction of arms., 1959-62 (Box 30)
  - Third Party., 1958-59 (Box 30)
  - Marshal Tito - Yugoslavia., 1963 (Box 30)
  - Trade with Russia., 1959-60 (Box 30)
  - Trujillo., 1961 (Box 30)
  - Tocsin., 1962-66 (Box 30)
  - U.S. Information agency., n.d. (Box 30)
  - J. Robert Oppenheimer., 1963 (Box 31)
  - Richard M. Nixon., 1963 (Box 31)
  - New Frontier - Plan for surrender., 1961-63 (Box 31)
  - Near and far east, India, Laos, Vietnam., 1963 (Box 31)
  - National Council of Churches., 1965 (Box 31)
  - World Youth Crusade for Freedom., 1965-66 (Box 31)
  - Los Angeles World Affairs Council., 1966-68 (Box 31)
  - Foundation for Economic Education., 1965-66 (Box 31)
  - Town Hall., 1966-68 (Box 31)
  - The Independent American., 1965-68 (Box 31)
  - We The People., 1965-67 (Box 31)
  - New England Rally for God, Family and Country., 1966-67 (Box 31)
  - Radio of Free Asia (KCFF)., 1966-68 (Box 31)
  - The Dan Smoot Report., 1968 (Box 31)
  - American Economic Foundation., 1963-68 (Box 31)
  - The Free Society Association., 1965-67 (Box 31)
  - American Association of Retired Persons., 1966-68 (Box 31)
  - African-American Affairs Association., 1967-68 (Box 31)
  - Committee of One Million., 1966-68 (Box 31)
  - Young Americans for Freedom., 1966-68 (Box 31)
  - Mannion Forum., 1967-68 (Box 31)
  - Americanism Education League., 1967-68 (Box 31)
  - California politics - Nixon, Shell, Jarvis, Kuchel, Wright., 1961 (Box 32)
  - Pubic Action Incorporated., 1964 (Box 32)
  - Adams Clayton Powell., 1963 (Box 32)
  - Karl Prussian Foundation (Heads Up)., 1964-66 (Box 32)
  - Portugal - Angola., 1963 (Box 32)
  - Pocket Testament League., n.d. (Box 32)
  - Patriotic Education., 1958-59 (Box 32)
  - Patriotic businesses and corporations., 1959 (Box 32)
  - Oxford, Miss - Riots. Walker., 1962 (Box 32)
  - Otepka, Otto - State Dept., 1963 (Box 32)
  - American Legion., 1966-68 (Box 32)
  - Oswald, Lee H. - Assassin., 1963-64 (Box 32)
  - Liberty Lobby., 1964-68 (Box 32)
  - America's Future., 1964-65 (Box 32)
  - Citizen's Committee for a free Cuba., 1964-68 (Box 32)
  - Americanism Educational League., 1967 (Box 32)
  - Christain Anti-Communism Crusade., 1966-68 (Box 32)
  - Africa., 1960-61 (Box 33)
  - Alaska., 1963 (Box 33)
  - Steve Allen., 1960 (Box 33)
  - American Traitors - Jessup, Hiss, Oppenheimer, Rosenberg, White, Ware, Lattimore, Service, Gold, etc., 1954-60 (Box 33)
  - Berlin., 1961 (Box 33)
  - Betancourt of Venezuela., 1962-63 (Box 33)
  - Braden, Thomas, W., 1963 (Box 33)
  - Brazil., 1959-63 (Box 33)
  - Brown, Governor., 1963 (Box 33)
  - Governor Brown - water, schools, metro, government., 1960-61 (Box 33)
  - Ralph Bunche., n.d. (Box 33)
  - Business men in communism., 1959 (Box 33)
  - Americanism Educational League., 1964-66 (Box 33)
  - Nelson Rockefeller., 1958-63; (2 folders) (Box 34)
  - J. Edgar Hoover., 1961-63 (Box 34)
  - Philip Jessup - World Court., 1961-62 (Box 34)
  - George Catlett Marshall., 1951 (Box 34)
  - Jo McCarthy., 1954-57 (Box 34)
  - Robert R. Murrow., 1958-61 (Box 34)
  - Labor - Walter Reuther. The Kennedy Boys., 1959 (Box 34)
  - Richard Milhous Nixon., 1959-62 (Box 34)
  - Richard Nixon's ambition., 1959-60 (Box 34)
  - Thomas H. Kuchel., 1963 (Box 34)
  - Church League of America., n.d. (Box 34)
  - Hall of Free Enterprise., 1964 (Box 34)
  - Herald of Freedom., 1964 (Box 34)
  - Freedom Press., 1964 (Box 34)
  - Christian Crusade., 1964 (Box 34)
  - Melville Burke., 1961 (Box 34)
  - J. Edgar Hoover., 1947-62 (Box 34)
  - Mayor Yorty and the CDC., 1961-62 (Box 34)
  - Venezuela and Betancourt., 1962-63 (Box 35)
  - Vetterli., 1961 (Box 35)
  - Voice of Americanism., 1966 (Box 35)
  - Barry Goldwater., 1963 (Box 35)
  - Walker, Maj. Gen. Edwin A., 1961-62 (Box 35)
  - West Berlin and West Germany., 1961 (Box 35)
  - Yugoslavia., 1961 (Box 35)
  - Book lists, reprints., n.d. (Box 35)
  - Speakers, programs, groups, anti-communists., 1962 and n.d. (Box 35)
- Records (Audio), n.d.
  - Calling all conservatives! (Box 36)
  - Communist trickery. How will the red butchers dispose of your family? (Box 36)
  - The fearless American. (Box 36)
  - Medicine leads the way. The poison and the antidote. (Box 36)
  - Cybernetic warfare. Are you sure communism hasn't brainwashed you? (Box 36)
  - Communist cancer. Is there still time to stop the Soviet Malignancy? (Box 36)
  - Red pipeline to Moscow. (Box 36)
  - For heaven's sake! A musical revue, written especially for the North American Ecumenical Youth Assembly., 1961 (Box 36)
- Books
  - Mental Robots. Caldwell, Idaho: Caxton., 1961 (Box 1)
  - American Opinion Dollar Reprint Series, 1961-1963; (7 issues) (Box 10)
    - "I saw Poland betrayed.", 1961 (Box 10)
    - "Nine men against America.", 1961 (Box 10)
    - "America's retreat from victory.", 1961 (Box 10)
    - "The tragedy of France.", 1962 (Box 10)
    - "The key to peace.", 1963 (Box 10)
    - "Color communism and common sense.", 1963 (Box 10)
    - "The invasion of Mississippi.", 1963 (Box 10)
  - The true aspects of the Algerian rebellion, published by the Ministere de L'Algerie, Cabinet du ministre., n.d. (Box 21)
  - No wonder we are losing. New York: The Bookmailer., 1958 (Box 25)
  - Terrible 1313 revisited. Chadwick, Idaho: The Caldwell Printers., 1963 (Box 25)
  - Brain washing in the high schools. New York: The Devin-Adair Company., 1958 (Box 25)
  - The California legislature. Sacramento, California: California State Printing Office., 1957 (Box 25)
  - The hope of the world. Dallas, Texas: Miller Publishing Company., 1958 (Box 25)
  - "Our invisible government and how it operates." Reprinted from The news and courier, Charleston, South Carolina., Oct 18, 1961 (Box 25)
  - Fallout protection, What to know and do about nuclear attack. U.S. Government Printing Office., 1961 (Box 25)
  - Censorship and survival. New York: The Bookmailer., 1961 (Box 25)
  - Immigration: Our open door policy. The American coalition of patriotic societies., [1962] (Box 25)
  - The fearful master. A second look at the United Nations. Boston, Los Angeles: Western Islands., 1964 (Box 25)
  - The fearful master. A second look at the United Nations. Boston, Los Angeles: Western Islands., 1965 (Box 25)
  - The Inhumanity of Urban Renewal. Springfield, Virginia: Crestwood Books., 1965 (Box 1)
  - The Law. New York: Foundation for Economic Education., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Out of Bondage. New Rochelle, New York: America's Future, (All American Book Digest vol.2)., [1956] (Box 1)
  - The Modern Conservative. Whittier, California: Constructive Action., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Pawns in the Game (4th edition). Los Angeles: St. George's Press., 1962 (Box 1)
  - America's Unelected Rulers. New Orleans: Conservative Society of America Publishing., 1962 (Box 1)
  - The Case of General Edwin A. Walker. New Orleans: Conservative Society of America Publishing., 1961 (Box 1)
  - The Silencers. New Orleans: Conservative Society of America Publishing., 1965 (Box 1)
  - The Big Decision. [Los Angeles]: Cvetic., [1959] (Box 1)
  - Men of the Far Right. New York: Pyramid Books., 1962 (Box 1)
  - The Fringe on Top. New York: American Features., 1962 (Box 1)
  - The Fabulous Future. America in 1980. New York: Dutton., 1956 (Box 1)
  - Your Rugged Constitution. Stanford University., 1950 (Box 1)
  - The United States as a Communist Nation... Chicago: Help Fight Communism., 1962 (Box 1)
  - The Lattimore Story. New York: Devin-Adair., 1953 (Box 1)
  - The Decline of the American Republic & How to Rebuild It. New Rochelle, New York: America's Future, 1957 (All-American Book Digest). (Box 1)
  - While You Slept. New Rochelle, New York: America's Future, 1956 (All American Book Digest). (Box 1)
  - The Pentagon Case. New York: Freedom Press., 1958 (Box 1)
  - Red Tide. n.p., 1962 (Box 1)
  - The Conscience of a Conservative. New York: Hillman Books., 1960 (Box 1)
  - Where I Stand. New York: McGraw., 1964 (Box 1)
  - The National Council of Churches. Glendale, California: Voice of Americanism Publishing. (Box 4)
  - Should Christians Fight Communism? Glendale, California: Voice of Americanism Publishing. (Box 1)
  - The Fearful Master. A Second Look at the United Nations. Boston: Western Islands (2 copies, variants)., 1964 (Box 1)
  - Terrible 1313 Revisited. Caldwell, Idaho: Caxton., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Design for Dedicational. Foreword by Richard Cardinal Cushing. New York: Bookmailer., 1958 (Box 2)
  - The Continuing Revolt. The Black Book on Red China. New York: Bookmailer., 1958 (Box 2)
  - The John Franklin Letters. New York: The Bookmailer., 1959 (Box 1)
  - Gold Swindle. The Story of Our Dwindling Gold. New York: Bookmailer., 1959 (Box 2)
  - Profiles in Courage. New York: Pocket Books, Incorporated., 1957 (Box 2)
  - A Program for Conservatives (revised edition). Chicago: Regnery., 1962 (Box 2)
  - A Business Man Looks at Communism (3rd. edition). January 1961. Wichita, Kansas: Koch. (Box 2)
  - "The American Tragedy, an Address..." 39th Annual Texas Manufacturers, Association... n.p., November 17, 1961 (Box 2)
  - And Not a Shot Is Fired. New Canaan, Connecticut: The Long House., 1962 (Box 2)
  - The Lesson of China's Loss. New York: Committee of One Million., n.d. (Box 2)
  - Vietnam, an Eye-Witness Account. Springfield, Virginia: Crestwood., 1964 (Box 2)
  - The Leadership of President Kennedy. Caldwell, Idaho. Caxton., 1964 (Box 2)
  - John F. Kennedy. What's Behind the Image? Washington, D.C.: Free World Press., 1960 (Box 2)
  - A GATT in Your Ribs. Washington, D.C.: Lewis. (Box 2)
  - The Facts about Communism. Tulsa, Oklahoma: Christian Crusade., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Communist America... Must it be? Tulsa, Oklahoma: Christian Crusade., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Economics in One Lesson. Rockefeller Center, New York: Pocket Books., 1952 (Box 2)
  - A Texan Looks at Lyndon. Canyon, Texas: Palo Duro Press., 1964 (Box 2)
  - The Soviet Stand on Germany. New York, New York: Crosscurrents Press., 1961 (Box 2)
  - Khruschev in America. New York, New York: Crosscurrents Press., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Keynes at Harvard. Veritas Foundation., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Revitalizing a Nation. Chicago: Heritage Foundation., 1952 (Box 3)
  - Red China's Secret Plans for Destroying America. Glendale, California: Voice of Americanism. (Box 3)
  - The "Social Gospel". Glendale, California: Voice of Americanism Publishing., (2 copies) (Box 3)
  - Our Invisible Government and How It Operates. [Uniondale, Pennsylvania: Malinowski]. (Box 3)
  - Fortress Cuba. Chicago: Regnery., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Mama Went to War. Sheperdsville, Kentucky: Victor Publishing., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Crisis Over Rhodesia. Baltimore, John Hopkins Press., 1967 (Box 3)
  - The Deep South Says No. New York: Ballantine Books., 1957 (Box 3)
  - Communist Manifesto. Chicago: Regnery., [1954] (Box 3)
  - The Republican Opportunity. New York: Duell, Sloan., 1962 (Box 3)
  - The Republican Opportunity in 1964. New York: Duell, Sloan. (Box 3)
  - No Wonder We Are Losing. New York: Bookmailer., 1958 (Box 3)
  - The Federal Reserve Conspiracy. Union, New York: Christian Educational Association., 1954 (Box 3)
  - For the Skeptic. Selected Readings on Communist Activity in United States of America. New York: The Bookmailer., 1959 (Box 3)
  - An Evil Tree. The Story of Communism. Forward by Charles F. Buddy, Bishop of San Diego. Milwaukee: Bruce Publishing., 1961 (Box 3)
  - Let's Take the Offensive. Nashville, Tennessee: The Parthenon Press., 1962 (Box 3)
  - Win Now or Lose All. Nashville, Tennessee: The Parthenon Press., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Pass the Poverty Please! Whittier, California: Constructive Action., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Essays from One Dozen Candles. The Americanist Library. Boston, Los Angeles: Western Islands., 1965 (Box 4)
    Gitlow, Benjamin. "The Whole of Their Lives."
    McCarthy, Joseph R. "America's Retreat From Victory."
    Smoot, Dan. "The Invisible Government."
    Lane, Arthut Bliss. "I Saw Poland Betrayed."
    Petro, Sylvester. "The Kohler Strike."
    Jordan, George Racey. "From Mayor Jordan's Diaries."
    Flynn, John T. "While You Slept."
    Toledana, Ralph de. "Seeds of Treason."
    Jarret, Garet. "The People's Pottage."
    Sisley. "France the Tragic Years."
    DuBerrier, Hilaire. "Background to Betrayal."
    Gordon, Rosalie M. "Nine Men Against America."
    Willoughby, Charles A. "Shanghai Conspiracy."
  - British Socialism is Destroying British Freedom. New York: National Economic Council., n.d. (Box 4)
  - Race and Reason. A Yankee View. Washington, D.C.: Public Affairs Press., 1961 (Box 4)
  - California Dynasty of Communism. Fullerton, California: [Heads Up]., n.d. (Box 4)
  - Reflections on Coming of Age. FEE Faces the Future. New York: Foundation for Economic Education, Incorporated., 1967 (Box 4)
  - Slightly to the Right! Whittier, California: Constructive Action., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Labor Union Monopoly. Chicago: Regnery., 1957 (Box 4)
  - Can We Preserve Our "American System" - in the Postwar World? Robnett., 1944 (Box 4)
  - The Liberal Papers. New York: Doubleday., 1962 (Box 4)
  - A Choice Not an Echo. Alton, Illinois: Marquette., 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Gravediggers. Alton, Illinois: Marquette., 1964 (Box 4)
  - Safe-not Sorry. Alton, Illinois: Pere Marquette Press., 1967 (Box 4)
  - Strike From Space. Alton, Illinois: Marquette., 1965 (Box 4)
  - The Sedition Case, Lowell, Arizona. Lutheran Research Society., 1953 (Box 4)
  - The Turning of the Tides. New Canaan, Connecticut: Long House., 1956 (Box 4)
  - The Bondage of the Free. Berkeley: Vanguard., 1966 (Box 4)
  - None Dare Call It Treason. Florissant, Mississippi: Liberty Bell Press., 1964 (Box 4)
  - World Government and International Assassination. Belmont, Massachusetts: American Opinion Reprints., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Right-to-Work Laws. Los Angeles: Institute of Industrial Relations, UCLA., 1958 (Box 4)
  - The Tenney Committee... The American Record. Tujunja, California: Standard Publishing., March 1952 (Box 5)
  - Zion's Trojan Horse. Hollywood, California: Standard Publishing., April 1954 (Box 5)
  - A program for Conservatives. Introduction by Senator Barry Goldwater. New York: Macfadden-Bartell Corporation., 1962 (Box 5)
  - Conquest or Consent (2nd edition). Boston: Forum., 1963 (Box 5)
  - Censorship and Survival. New York: Bookmailer., 1961 (Box 5)
  - The Voter's Presidential Handbook. New York: McDowell., 1960 (Box 5)
  - Red Star Over Cuba. New York: Hillman/MacFadden., 1961 (Box 5)
  - The Anti-Defamation League (5th Canadian Printing). Flesherton, Canada: Canadian Intelligence Publishing., 1951 (Box 5)
  - The House of Secrets. New York: Duell, Sloan., 1959 (Box 5)
  - Thugs and Communists (2nd Printing). Long Island, New York: Public Opinion., 1962 (Box 5)
  - Organized banking. New York: Holt., 1918 (Box 8)
  - By vote of the people. New York: Scribners., 1946 (Box 8)
  - Inside the State Department. New York: Comet Press Books., 1956 (Box 12)
  - House of Rockefeller. Washington D.C.: All America House., 1959 (Box 8)
  - The iron curtain over America. Dallas: Wilkinson., 1956 (Box 12)
  - The California legislature. Sacramento, California: State Printing Office., 1942, 1950 and 1957 (Box 12)
  - God and man at Yale. Chicago: Regnery., 1951 (Box 11)